Andrejs Sorstkins

Software Engineer

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: andrejs232@gmail.com

Phone: +447708230365

Web Site: https://andreyshor.github.io/

OBJECTIVE

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of back-end, front-end development requirements and have deep knowledge of security principles and tools. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 2 years of related experience. I

have had professional experience of working with private clients in the Freelance market industry, and research experience in the university laboratory environment witch such topics as BCI (Brain Computer Interface). Computer Vision and Evolution Algorithm

EXPERIENCE

Latvia

Jun 2019 - Jan 2020

Frontend Developer/ Manager

Arcona

This was contract role for fixed time period.

First part of my role was to develop web site solution for company.

Second part included managment of communication and work with design team and printing house

Colchester, United Kingdom

Oct 2019 - Mar 2022

Full stack developer

Freelance/self-employed

I was making website for private clients. Company ranges from small to medium size corporations. Example of my work:

- 1. Transport Company https://lazarus.lv/
- 2. Iceco (medical company) https://greens.lv/

Colchester, United Kingdom

Oct 2019 - May 2022

Software Developer

Essex University

I made good number of hobby and scientific projects during my education.

- 1. COVID illness runner, this game fully written on Java, in simple words, I was tired out of COVID and create game about it for on of the university assignments: https://github.com/AndreyShor/COVID-ilness_runner/tree/main/src
- 2. A* search algorithm (Artificial Intelligence) for 8 puzzle problem, it was mainly education problem in AI field, bet it consume so much my mental energy that I would lie to highlight it: https://github.com/AndreyShor/8_puzzle_problem
- 3. Socket based online game in console, where n number of people are playing football: https://github.com/AndreyShor/VirtualBall
- 4. Evaluation Algorithm Project, this topic was very personal for me, because I am queries how evaluation is working, I create my little library for Genetic Algorithm (GA), and some small research project about bloat in Genetic programming: (GP)

4.1 GA

https://github.com/AndreyShor/evaluation_algorithm_little_library/blob/main/E_A_little_lib.ipynb

4.2 GP: https://github.com/AndreyShor/Genetic_programming_math/blob/main/Mini-Project_Andrejs_Sorstkins_GP.ipynb

5. Face Recognition Project, I have video only, haven't put code to github https://youtu.be/3FT9app4qUg

EDUCATION

Colchester, United Kingdom

Oct 2019 - Jun 2022

Computer Science

University of Essex

Grade: First Class (Hons.)

Graduated top of degree class (Computer Science and electronical engeeniring) achieving First Class

(with Honors)
Modules included:

Computer Security, Network Security, Articial Inelegance, Evaluation Algorithms, Algorithmic Game Theory, Databases Architecture, Operating Systems, Languages and Compilers, Network Fundamentals

and more

Dissertation Project:

Brain Computer Interface and Virtual Home. Solution was made to move and control electronical devices by using motor cortex (imagine different parts of your body)

Folkestone, United Kingdom

Sep 2017 - Aug 2019

A level

Earlscliffe College

A levels included:

- Economics
- Mathematics
- · Physics
- · Geography (Human and Physical)

LANGUAGES

SKILLS

English Advanced

Russian

Advanced

Latvian Native Java

JavaScript MySQL

Angular PUG and SCSS

Python

MongoDb React

HTML and CSS
Kali Linux